Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
ステラ！
Stella!
She's alive.
（チセ）
生きてる…
She isn't as pale as she was before.
顔色も
さっきよりは悪くない
（カルタフィルス）
目がくらんだでしょ
You must be dizzy.
こっちへ来てよ
Come here.
It's not dead.
（カルタフィルス）
死んではいないよ
Long time no see.
久しぶり
Joseph.
（チセ）ヨセフ…
When did we last meet? At the graveyard?
（カルタフィルス）
君と こうして会うのは
墓場以来かな
I could never forget you after what you'd done to me.
手ひどくやられたから
忘れられないよ
He doesn't remember.
（チセ）
覚えてない？
You always cause me so much trouble.
本当に
余計なことばっかりしてくれるね
君は
Well, it's fine.
まあいいや
You accepted my deal, after all.
君は
取り引きに応じてくれたんだから
You're the same as me.
君は僕と同じだ
Your curse is as powerful as mine.
同じくらい強い呪いを受けてる
I'm cursed to live on forever.
僕は ひたすら生き続ける呪い
You're cursed to die.
君は死に向かう呪い
So give me your left arm.
だからさ その左腕 僕に頂戴よ
It's my arm that you want?
あなたが欲しいのは
私の腕？
Yeah.
That part looks the most usable right now.
今のところ
それが いちばん使えそうだからね
I'll give you a part of me in exchange.
その対価に
僕も君に 自分の一部を差し出すよ
That way, you'll have a body that can never die.
そうすれば 君は
いつまでも死なない体になるんだ
I can't trust you.
（チセ）信用… できない
じゃあ 君
ほかに選択肢があるとでも？
Are you saying you have another option?
やるんだよ
You're doing it.
Do I just need to give you my arm?
この腕を
そのまま移せばいいの？
（カルタフィルス）
その前に 拒絶反応が出ないか
確かめようか
First, let's make sure my body doesn't reject it.
There.
（カルタフィルス）
はい 次は君の番
Now it's your turn.
What? Are you scared?
あれ？ やっぱり怖い？
You might be freed from your curse.
呪いから
解放されるかもしれないのに
大丈夫だよ
It's okay.
You won't change into another form or anything.
違う形に
変わったりするわけじゃないし
（チセ）変わったとしても…
（カルタフィルス）ん？
Even if I did...
かまわない
I wouldn't care.
Why are you so...
なんで そんなに…
What?
Nothing. I was just thinking about how I still hate you.
やっぱり 僕は君が嫌いだなって…
手伝ってあげるね
I'll help you.
ハア… ハア…
（カルタフィルス）はい 移植完了
There.
Transplant complete.
（チセ）ハア… ハア…
Don't worry, you won't die just from bleeding.
（カルタフィルス）
大丈夫
血が出たくらいで死なないよ
It doesn't seem like my body's rejecting it.
拒絶反応はないみたいだ
Your eyeball makes the world look bright and shiny.
君の目玉は
なんだか世界が
キラキラして見えるなあ
うらやましいなあ
I envy you.
ハア… ハア…
We're the only people in this world who see what we do.
（カルタフィルス）
僕ら この世界で唯一
同じものが見えてるんだ
呪いが なじんだら
その腕をもらうよ
I'll have your arm once the curse settles in.
Don't worry. It'll all be done while you're asleep.
安心してよ
眠ってる間に
全部 終わるから
I'm going to borrow the power that's left in your eye.
目に残ってる君の力を
借りるね
What are you...
（チセ）何… を？
I told you. I hate you.
言ったろ？
僕は君が嫌いだって
So...
だからさ…
What is this place?
何？ ここ…
I don't know...
（チセ）
知らない…
No...
（チセ）
違う… 懐かしい
It's nostalgic.
（ドアが開く音）
知ってる
I know this place.
Sorry, Chise.
（智花(ちか)）ごめんね 智世(ちせ)
Mom?
（チセ）お母さん…
Welcome home, Mom!
（幼いチセ）
おかえりなさい お母さん
Thanks for watching the house.
（智花）お留守番 ありがとう
怖いこと なかった？
It wasn't too scary, was it?
Yeah, Fumiki was with me, so everything's okay.
史輝(ふみき)といたから 大丈夫だよ
Okay.
（智花）そっか
Fumiki's lucky he takes after his dad.
史輝は お父さんに似て
よかったわね
This is before my dad and little brother vanished.
（チセ）
これ まだ お父さんと弟が
消える前の…
Fumiki's a good boy.
（幼いチセ）史輝は いい子ね〜
あっ あのね おしめね
Hey, I can change his diaper now!
替えられるように
なったの
（幼いチセ）えへん
You're right.
ホントだ！
ん〜 ありがとう！
Thank you.
You're a good girl, too, Chise.
智世もホントに いい子ね
（幼いチセ）エヘヘ
Mommy, Mommy, I want to help make dinner.
お母さん お母さん
私も ご飯 作るの手伝う！
（智花）わあ 本当？
Really?
じゃあ 何してもらおっかな
What should I have you do?
I'll do anything.
（チセ）
そうだ…
That's right.
She used to have a really happy smile.
あんな顔して
すごくうれしそうに
笑う人だったんだ
Welcome home, Dad!
（幼いチセ）
おかえりなさい！ お父さん
（夕輝(ゆうき)）おっと！
Just a sec.
ぬれるから ちょっと待てよ
You're gonna get wet.
Welcome home, Yuuki.
（智花）おかえり 夕輝
You're home late.
今日は遅かったのね
Hurry!
（夕輝）ああ
（幼いチセ）早く〜
Yeah.
I'm home, Chise.
（夕輝）ただいま 智世
（幼いチセ）おかえりなさい！
Welcome home!
（夕輝）
おい ちょっと！ 歩けないだろ
Hey! I can't walk!
Hey.
I guess I took after my dad.
（チセ）
お父さん似だったんだな
（夕輝）ふわ〜あ…
Is work tough?
お仕事 大変？
I have more night shifts now.
（夕輝）最近 夜勤 増やしたからな
I'm sorry. I wish I could work, too.
ごめんね
私も働ければいいんだけど…
You already take care of things around the house, Chika.
智花は
家のこと してくれてるだろ？
Besides, Chise's like you.
それに 智世は智花に似て
マズい体質だから
She's got a frail body.
I feel better with you around her.
そばにいてくれたほうが
俺も安心だよ
Thanks, Yuuki.
ありがとう 夕輝
Frail body...
（チセ）
体質…
Mom was the same as me?
お母さんも 私と同じ？
This is my memory.
（チセ）
これは私の記憶
He's keeping me in a dream so that I don't wake up.
私は あいつに
起きないように
夢を見せられている
ハッ！ カル…
Car—
No.
違う
You aren't him.
あなた… あいつじゃない
I'm a fragment of him that's been chopped off.
僕は… 切り離された あれのかけら
あれは いろんなものをくっつけて
取り込んできた
He's attached and assumed all kinds of things.
Which is the real him, what he even was to begin with...
本当のあれが どれなのか
そもそも 自分が何だったのか
none of it is clear anymore.
もう分からなくなってるんだよ
Why is he making me see all this stuff from my past?
（チセ）
どうして こんな昔のことを
私に見せるの？
Probably to upset you.
（カルタフィルス）多分 嫌がらせ
That there is hurting you, but it's also protecting you.
（カルタフィルス）
それは君を傷つけてもいるけれど
守ってもいる
It's the reason you're able to talk to something like me.
君が こうして
僕のようなものと話せるのも
そのせいだ
You're...
（チセ）あなたは…
You don't want to touch me.
（カルタフィルス）
僕に触らないほうがいい
Not until you're ready.
決心がつくまでは
Ready?
決心？
It's okay, I'll calm him down.
いいよ 俺があやしてくる
（智花）ありがとう
Thanks.
Dad, are you going somewhere?
（幼いチセ）お父さん？
どこか行くの？
（夕輝）智世も…
（幼いチセ）ん？
Chise, do you want to...
No, I'll be right back.
（夕輝）
いや… ちょっとだけだから
待っててな
Wait here.
Well, good night.
ほら おやすみ
うん いってらっしゃ〜い
Come back soon.
Dad never...
それから お父さんは 二度と…
（チセ）ダメ！
No!
...came back home.
（チセ）
帰ってこなかったんだ
That's all you remember.
（カルタフィルス）
君の記憶は そこまでだから
この扉は開かないよ
That door won't open.
Yuuki?
（智花）夕輝？
That's right.
（チセ）
そうか この日から…
Ever since this day...
（ガシャン！）
（智花）きゃあ！
Come on, again?
（パートＡ）
ねえ ちょっと… また？
I'm sorry.
すみません！
Something's odd lately.
（パートＡ）最近 なんか変なのよ
Ever since Hatori-san showed up, right?
（パートＢ）
羽鳥(はとり)さんが来てからでしょ？
Want some help?
（妖怪）助けてやろうか？
おかえりなさ…
Welcome h—
（智花）ハア…
What's wrong?
（幼いチセ）どうしたの？
I was the one who said you can't be scared.
（智花）
怖がっちゃいけないって言ったのは
お母さんなのにね
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
It'll be okay.
大丈夫よ
（智花）
大丈夫…
It'll be okay.
大丈夫
（幼いチセ）さん…
Help!
助けて！
Help, Mom!
助けて！ お母さん！
Get out!
出ていきなさい！ 早く！
Now!
（幼いチセ）わあ〜ん！
（壁をたたく音）
（隣人）おい！
Hey, it's midnight! Shut up!
夜中に うるせえぞ！
（智花）
守らなきゃ… 守らなきゃ
I have to protect her.
I have to be strong.
しっかりしなきゃ
That guy who was protecting them isn't around lately.
（妖怪Ａ）
最近 いつもの守(も)り男がおらんな
（妖怪Ｂ）
かわいそうに… 愛想を尽かしたか
Poor thing. He must have gotten sick of her.
An abandoned woman.
（妖怪Ａ）捨てられた女
（妖怪Ｂ）捨てられた娘
An abandoned daughter.
（妖怪Ａ）哀れで うまそうだ
Pitiful and appetizing.
（智花）ハア… ハア…
（智花）はい… そうですか
Yes.
I see.
はい… 分かりました
I understand.
Popular job listings!
It'll be okay.
大丈夫よ…
あの子は私が守らなきゃ
I have to protect her.
大丈夫よ
It'll be okay.
大丈夫
ね？ 私一人だって… 大丈夫
I'll be okay on my own.
大丈夫…
It'll be okay.
あの子がいなくなれば
It would be so much easier for me without her.
もっと
私は楽になれるのに
That's crazy! That's crazy!
そんなこと… そんなこと！
But, if she weren't here...
（智花）
でも あの子がいなければ…
I shouldn't...
（智花）あなたなんか…
have given birth to you.
産まなきゃよかった
I shouldn't have given birth to you.
あなたなんか…
産まなきゃよかった
M... om...
（幼いチセ）お母さ…
（幼いチセ）ゲフッ… ゴホッ
（智花）
私 何をしたの？
What have I done?
（幼いチセ）ゴホッ ゴホッ…
Mom?
お母さん？
I'm sorry, Chise.
ごめんね 智世…
Please forgive me.
許してね
To upset me?
（チセ）嫌がらせ…
嫌がらせね
To upset me?
うん… すごい嫌がらせだ
This is really upsetting.
お母さん
Mom...
I shouldn't have given birth to you.
（智花）
あなたなんて
産まなきゃよかった
It's your fault.
あなたのせいで…
It's because your body is so weak.
あなたが こんな体だったから
Why?
なんで… なんでよ？
死ねばよかったのに
You should have died.
Die, die, die, die, die, die, die... Die!
死ね 死ね 死ね
死ね 死ね 死ね！
死ね！ 死ねえええ！
Why didn't you finish me off, then?
じゃあ なんで
最後まで やらなかったの？
You aren't my real mom.
あなたは…
本当のお母さんじゃない
あなたは私の中のお母さん
You're the mom that exists inside of me.
The mom that I created after she strangled me.
お母さんに首を絞められた
私が作ったお母さん
I'm glad I talked to Nevin.
ネヴィンと話せてよかった
Angelica-san, Simon-san, Alice and Renfred,
アンジェリカさん
サイモンさん
アリスたちに
リンデルさんや妖精の国の人たち
Lindel-san, the people of the fairy world...
Ruth, Silky, Stella,
ルツ
シルキー
ステラ
Elias...
エリアス
I'm glad I got to meet all kinds of people.
いろんな人たちに会えてよかった
Without them, I would have died before I'd met you.
そうじゃなきゃ
私は あなたに会う前に
きっと死んでたから
Forgive me.
（智花）許して…
Forgive me, Chise.
許して 智世
Forgive me.
許して…
You endured for my sake, didn't you?
お母さんは私のために
頑張ってくれたんだよね
You endured and endured, but in the end...
頑張って 頑張って
それでも 最後に…
You're free.
（ネヴィン）君は自由だ
I won't forgive you.
許さないよ
お母さんのこと 大好きだった
I loved you, Mom.
I have lots of happy memories with you.
楽しい思い出だって
たくさんあった
And yet, ever since that day,
I couldn't remember any of them.
なのに あの日から
そんなの全然 思い出せなくて
But thanks to you,
でも…
お母さんのおかげで 私は
自分よりも放っておけない
好きなヒトに会えた
I met someone that I cared for even more than myself.
I thought he was strong,
but he turned out to be pretty troubled.
しっかりしてると思ったら
かなり困ったヒトだったけどね
Yeah.
So...
だから…
だからさ
Thanks for letting go of me that day.
ありがとう
あのとき あの手を離してくれて
I won't forgive you.
許さないけど…
I won't forget you yet,
私は まだ あなたを忘れないけど
but I'm going to leave you and move on.
あなたを置いて 前に進むよ
Are you ready?
決心はついた？
What are you?
あなたは何？
（カルタフィルス）
僕は生かし続けるもの
I'm what keeps one living on.
The curse and blessing that was given for his sake.
彼のために与えられた呪いと祝福
Joseph.
ヨセフ… カルタフィルスの？
Cartaphilus?
They planted me in you, and you're trying to accept me.
（カルタフィルス）
彼らは 君に僕を蒔(ま)き
君は僕を受け入れようとしている
So as long as you wish to live, I'll be your blessing.
だから 君が生きたいと望むかぎり
僕は君の祝福になろう
Even if that means tearing at what
consumes and protects you for all eternity.
君を蝕(むしば)みながら守るケダモノと
永遠に噛(か)み裂き合ってでも
What do... What do you desire?
（チセ）
あなたは… あなたは何を望むの？
（カルタフィルス）僕？
Me?
What's the price?
（チセ）対価は？
What you say sounds good only for me.
私にだけ都合がよく聞こえるから
There's one wish that I've heard many times.
１つだけ…
聞こえ続けた望みがある
Can you grant that for me?
君は それを
かなえることができるの？
It looks like it's starting to set in.
（カルタフィルス）
そろそろ なじんできたみたいだ
フッ… 醜いなあ
How vile.
Just like me.
僕と同じだ
Y-You're awake—
お前 起きて…
（チセ）
私も あなたのやり方をまねるよ
I'm going to do things the way you do.
望みが かなえられるかどうかは
分からない
I don't know if I can grant you your wish.
ただ… 聞いて なんとかしようと
動くことはできる
But I can hear you out, and try to do something.
"Help me."
（カルタフィルス）
助けて
助けて！ 助けて…
For centuries, for millennia,
何百年も何千年も
they've been shouting, "Help me."
彼らは ずうっと
そう叫んできた
I don't know why you desire this.
（チセ）私は知らない
あなたたちが
どうして そう望んでいるのか
Why, when you think as you do, you still do this.
そう思ってるのに
どうして こんなことしてるのか…
Why you've done this.
してきたのか
So I'm going to find out.
だから 知りに行く
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
（チセ）
ヨセフの真実に触れようとする少女
The girl tries to make sense of Joseph's truth.
Meanwhile, the mage, having lost the girl,
loses his human form, and is forced to wander.
一方 少女を失った魔法使いは
人の形を失い さまようしかなく…
（カルタフィルス）
見たのか？ 僕を…
You saw?
You saw me?
僕の いつかを！
My past?